<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on Yuri</title>
    <link>https://yp-alves.github.io/Yuri_Portfolio/techs/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on Yuri</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Yuri</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 19:47:09 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yp-alves.github.io/Yuri_Portfolio/techs/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rain Prediction</title>
      <link>https://yp-alves.github.io/Yuri_Portfolio/portfolio/defect_prediction-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 19:47:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yp-alves.github.io/Yuri_Portfolio/portfolio/defect_prediction-project/</guid>
      <description>This project analyzes meteorological data from a weather station in Niterói, Brazil, to develop a machine learning model capable of predicting rainfall based on various weather features.
Project Overview The dataset contains weather-related measurements such as temperature, humidity, wind speed, and atmospheric pressure. The objective was to explore the data, identify patterns, and train predictive models to classify whether or not it will rain.
Methodology Data Preprocessing: Cleaning and handling missing values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defect Prediction in Truck Air Systems</title>
      <link>https://yp-alves.github.io/Yuri_Portfolio/portfolio/rain_prediction-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 19:47:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yp-alves.github.io/Yuri_Portfolio/portfolio/rain_prediction-project/</guid>
      <description>Project Overview In this project, data science techniques were applied to optimize the maintenance planning for a transportation company&amp;rsquo;s truck fleet, specifically focusing on the air system.
Approach
1.Data Analysis and Preprocessing:
The data related to truck air system maintenance was analyzed and preprocessed. This included handling encoded columns and missing data to ensure the dataset was clean and suitable for modeling.
2.Model Training and Evaluation:
Various machine learning models were used to predict air system failures, including Random Forest, Gradient Boosting, and Naive Bayes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spam Filter Project</title>
      <link>https://yp-alves.github.io/Yuri_Portfolio/portfolio/spam_filter-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 19:47:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yp-alves.github.io/Yuri_Portfolio/portfolio/spam_filter-project/</guid>
      <description>In this project, we&amp;rsquo;re going to create a spam filter that classifies new messages with an accuracy greater than 80% — so we expect that more than 80% of the new messages will be classified correctly as spam or ham(non-spam). To do that, we&amp;rsquo;ll use the multinomial Naive Bayes algorithm along with a dataset of 5,572 SMS messages that are already classified by humans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advertising Project</title>
      <link>https://yp-alves.github.io/Yuri_Portfolio/portfolio/advertising-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 19:47:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yp-alves.github.io/Yuri_Portfolio/portfolio/advertising-project/</guid>
      <description>This project analyzes an e-learning company that wants to promote one of its products by investing in advertising. We will thoroughly analyze the e-learning market and develop a targeted advertising campaign to achieve this goal.
The company provided data from a survey where users of its platform informed personal data, goals, and availability to purchase products. The task is to define the best markets to invest in advertising.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Currency Project</title>
      <link>https://yp-alves.github.io/Yuri_Portfolio/portfolio/russian-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 19:47:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yp-alves.github.io/Yuri_Portfolio/portfolio/russian-project/</guid>
      <description>An analysis was carried out using Russia&amp;rsquo;s exchange rate data to assess how the country&amp;rsquo;s economy behaves in times of international conflict.
In this project we use Pandas and Matoplotlib to analyze our data and create an image that tells their story.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
